<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>John 8 32</title>
    <description>And ye shall know the truth, and the truth shall make you free.
</description>
    <link>https://john8-32.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://john8-32.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 20:37:45 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 20:37:45 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Traits of Rebekah</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;background-&quot;&gt;Background:-&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah died in Kirjatharba at the age of Hundred and seven and twenty. Abraham was old and stricken in age. He said his eldest servant of his house “Go unto my country, and to my kindred, and take a wife unto my son Isaac”. The servant asked Abraham, what if the woman is not willing to follow? Abraham said his servant, the LORD of heaven sware to me saying “He shall send his angel before thee” and you shall take a wife to my son. The servant took ten camels from his master and departed to Mesopotamia, unto the city of Nahor. He made his camels to kneel down without the city by a well of water at the time of evening. Then he said “O LORD GOD of my master Abraham, i pray thee, send me good speed this day and shew kindness unto my master Abraham”. And he continued “The damsel to whom i shall say, Let down thy pitcher, i pray thee, that i may drink; and she shall say, Drink and i will give thy camels drink also: let the same be she that thou hast appointed for thy servant Issac”. It came to pass, Rebekah came out, who was born to Bethuel, son of Milcah, the wife of Nahor, Abraham’s brother, with her pitcher upon her shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;characteristics-of-rebekah-&quot;&gt;Characteristics of Rebekah:-&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-the-damsel-was-very-fair-to-look-upon-a-virgin-neither-has-any-man-known-her-and-she-went-down-to-the-well-and-filled-her-pitcher-and-came-up-genesis-24-16&quot;&gt;1. And the damsel was very fair to look upon, a virgin, neither has any man known her: and she went down to the well, and filled her pitcher, and came up. Genesis 24: 16.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proverb 31: 30 says Favor is deceitful, and beauty is vain: but a woman that feats the LORD, she shall be praised. Verse 10 says “Who can find a virtuous woman? for her price is far above rubies.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 Peter 3: 4. But let it be the hidden man of the heart, in that which is not corruptible, even the ornament of meek and quiet spirt, which is in the sight of GOD of great price. 5. For after this manner in the old time the holy women also, who trusted in GOD, adorned themselves, being in subjection unto their own husbands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 Timothy 2: 9. In like manner also, that women adorn themselves in modest apparel, with modesty and sobriety; not with braided hair, or gold, or pearls, or costly array; 11. Let the woman learn in silence with all subjection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-the-servant-ran-to-meet-her-and-said-let-me-i-pray-thee-drink-a-little-water-of-thy-pitcher-and-she-said-drink-my-lord-and-she-hasted-and-let-down-her-pitcher-upon-her-hand-and-gave-him-drink-and-when-she-had-done-giving-him-drink-she-said-i-will-draw-for-thy-camels-also-until-they-have-done-drinking-and-she-hasted-and-emptied-her-pitcher-into-the-trough-and-ran-again-unto-the-well-to-draw-water-and-drew-for-all-his-camels-genesis-24-17-20&quot;&gt;2. And the servant ran to meet her, and said, Let me, I pray thee, drink a little water of thy pitcher. And she said, Drink my lord: and she hasted, and let down her pitcher upon her hand, and gave him drink. And when she had done giving him drink, she said, I will draw for thy camels also, until they have done drinking. And she hasted, and emptied her pitcher into the trough, and ran again unto the well to draw water, and drew for all his camels. Genesis 24: 17-20.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hard worker - she understood, he came from distance and gave water to her camels, She was practiced to work hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proverb 31: 13 - 17, describes about virtuous woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She seeketh wool, and flax, and worketh willingly with her hands. She is like the merchants’s ships; she bringeth her food from afar. She riseth also while it is yet night, and giveth meat to her household, and a portion to her maidens. She considereth a field, and buyeth it: with the fruit of her hands she planteth a vineyard. She considereth a field, and buyeth it: with the fruit of her hands she planteth a vineyard. She girdeth her lions with strength, and strengtheneth her arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-said-whose-daughter-art-thou-tell-me-i-pray-thee-is-there-room-in-thy-fathers-house-for-us-to-lodge-in-and-she-said-unto-him-i-am-the-daughter-of-bethuel-the-son-of-milcah-which-she-bare-unto-nahor-she-said-moreover-unto-him-we-have-both-straw-and-provender-enough-and-room-to-lodge-in-genesis-24-22---25&quot;&gt;3. And said, Whose daughter art thou? tell me, i pray thee: is there room in thy father’s house for us to lodge in? And she said unto him, I am the daughter of Bethuel the son of Milcah, which she bare unto Nahor. She said moreover unto him, we have both straw and provender enough, and room to lodge in. Genesis 24: 22 - 25.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebekah was very kind, She told the servant “We have both straw and provender enough, and room to lodge in”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proverb 31: 20 - She stretcheth out her hand to the poor; yea, she reacheth forth her hands to the needy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-the-damsel-ran-and-told-them-of-her-mothers-house-these-things-genesis-24-28&quot;&gt;4. And the damsel ran, and told them of her mother’s house these things. Genesis 24: 28.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebekah Ran to her home and let her family know about all the things happened at the well. It is important for a woman that it protects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-they-said-we-will-call-the-damsel-and-enquire-at-her-mouth-and-they-called-rebekah-and-said-unto-her-wilt-thou-go-with-this-man-and-she-said-i-will-go&quot;&gt;5. And they said, We will call the damsel, and enquire at her mouth. And they called Rebekah, and said unto her, Wilt thou go with this man? And she said, I will go.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rebekah told “I will go”. She was mentally prepared to leave her family and ready to live with her husband’s family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Psalms 45: 10, 11. Hearken, O daughter,  and consider, and incline thine ear; forget also thine own people, and thy father’s house; So shall the king greatly desire thy beauty: for he is thy LORD; and worship thou him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-she-had-said-unto-the-servant-what-man-is-this-that-walketh-in-the-field-to-meet-us-and-the-servant-had-said-it-is-my-master-therefore-she-took-a-vail-and-covered-herself-genesis-24-64&quot;&gt;6. For she had said unto the servant, What man is this that walketh in the field to meet us? And the servant had said, It is my master: therefore she took a vail, and covered herself. Genesis 24: 64.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebekah “took a vail, and covered herself”. This shows her humility and meekness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-issac-brought-her-into-his-mother-sarahs-tent-and-took-rebekah-and-she-became-his-wife-and-he-loved-her-and-issac-was-comforted-after-his-mothers-death&quot;&gt;7. And Issac brought her into his mother Sarah’s tent, and took Rebekah, and she became his wife; and he loved her: and Issac was comforted after his mother’s death.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebekah became Isaac’s wife, “and he loved her: and Issac was comforted after his mother’s death”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://john8-32.github.io/rebekah/traits-of-Rebekah.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://john8-32.github.io/rebekah/traits-of-Rebekah.html</guid>
        
        <category>Rebekah</category>
        
        <category>Characteristics</category>
        
        
        <category>Rebekah</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
