<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>John 8 32</title>
    <description>And ye shall know the truth, and the truth shall make you free.
</description>
    <link>https://john8-32.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://john8-32.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 20:49:39 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 20:49:39 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Four Dimensions of GOD&#39;s Love</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction-&quot;&gt;Introduction:-&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ephesians 3: 18&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;May be able to comprehend with all saints what is the breadth, and length, and depth, and height;&lt;/em&gt; Ephesians 3: 18 describes the four Dimensions of GOD’s Love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;breadth-of-gods-love&quot;&gt;1. Breadth of God’s Love&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Revelation 5: 9 - And they sung a new song, saying Thou art worthy to take the book, and to open the seals thereof: for thou wast slain, and hast redeemed us to God by thy blood out of every kindred, and tongue, and people, and nation;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This revelation says God redeemed every kindred, and tongue, and people, and nations by his blood. This refers how wide &lt;em&gt;(breadth)&lt;/em&gt; is God’s love. Actually it includes everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Revelation 7: 9-10 - After this i beheld, and, lo, a great multitude, which no man could number, of all nations, and kindreds, and people, and tongues, stood before the throne, and before the Lamb, clothed with white robes, and palms in their hands; And cried with a loud voice, saying, Salvation to our God which sitteth upon the throne, and unto the Lamb.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This revelation says A great multitude, which no man could number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;length-of-gods-love&quot;&gt;2. Length of God’s Love&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jeremiah 31: 3 - The LORD hath appeared of old unto me, saying, Yea, I have loved thee with an everlasting love: therefore with lovingkindness have i drawn thee.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here the LORD appeared and told Jeremiah “I have loved thee with an everlasting love: “ everlasting love can be interpreted as Endless love. So the length of God’s Love is Endless and it cant be measured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;depth-of-gods-love&quot;&gt;3. Depth of God’s Love&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philippians 2: 5 - 8 - Let this mind be in you, which was also in Christ Jesus: Who, being in the form of God, though        it not robbery to be equal with GOD: But made himself of no reputation, and took upon him the form of a servant, and was made in the likeness of men: And being found in fashion as a man, he humbled himself, and became obedient unto death, even the death of the cross.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How low God can came? This verse says “being found in fashion as a man, he humbled himself, and became obedient unto death, even the death of the cross”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOD Came to earth for what kind of people? Roman 3: 10-18 - Talks about Jesus died for what kind of people ??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roman 3: 10-18 As it is written, there is none righteous, no, not one: There is none that understandeth, there is note that seeketh after GOD. They all are gone out of the way, they are together become unprofitable; there is none that doeth good, no not one. Their thoat is an open sepulchre; with their tongue they have used deceit; the poison of asps is unter their lips: Whose mouth is full of cursing and bitterness: Their feet are swift to shed blood: Destruction and misery are in their ways: And the way of peace have they not known: There is no fear of God before their eyes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roman 5: 6, 8, 10.  These verses says How were we? when God came to rescue us? We were without strength, we were sinners, we were ungodly, we were enemies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For when we were yet without strength, in due time Christ died for the ungodly. But God commendeth his love toward us, in that, while we were yet sinners, Christ died for us. For if, when we were enemies, we were reconciled to God by the death of his Son, much more, being reconciled, we shall be saved by his life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These verses says How depth God’s love can go to save us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;height-of-gods-love&quot;&gt;4. Height of God’s Love&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salvation is not just about forgiveness of Sin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ephesians 5: 26-27 - That he might sanctify and cleanse it with the washing of water by the word, That he might present it to himself a glorious church, not having spot, or wrinkle, or any such thing; but that it should be holy and without blemish.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://john8-32.github.io/godslove/dimensions-of-Gods-love.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://john8-32.github.io/godslove/dimensions-of-Gods-love.html</guid>
        
        <category>God</category>
        
        <category>Love</category>
        
        <category>Dimensions</category>
        
        
        <category>GodsLove</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Noting can separate us from God&#39;s Love</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction-&quot;&gt;Introduction:-&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is based on the scriptures &lt;em&gt;Romans 8: 35-39&lt;/em&gt;. These scriptures clearly says There is nothing, absolutely nothing can separate us from God’s Love. Paul narrate this truth Roman people in an exiting way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who shall separate us from the love of Christ? shall tribulation, or distress, or persecution, or famine, or nakedness, or peril, or sword? As it is written, For thy sake we are killed all the day long; we are accounted as sheep for the slaughter. Nay, in all these things we are more than conquerors through him that loved us. For i am persuaded, that neither death, nor life, nor angels, nor principalities, nor powers, nor things present, not things to come, Nor height, nor depth, nor any other creature, shall be able to separate us from the love of God, which is in Christ Jesus our Lord. *Romans 8: 35-3*&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gods-love&quot;&gt;God’s Love.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Bible everywhere we can see God’s Love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Creation of the World.
    God created everything a human will ever need, just before creating human, then made him to rule everything.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The very famous verse John 3: 16 says &lt;em&gt;For God so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son, that  whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have everlasting life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The people of Nineveh were living a wicked life. God Chose Jonah to proclaim judgment to Nineveh. The people of Nineveh were so cruel, so Jonah wanted the Nineveh to be perished. He resisted and attempted to flee. Eventually Jonah went to Nineveh and prophesied against Nineveh. People of the city repent and God forgive them. Jonah was furious, and he beseeched God to kill him. The request was denied when God caused a tree to grow over him, giving him shade. It was grateful, Jonah’s anger returned next day, when God sent a worm to eat the plant, now Jonah tells God that it would be better if he were dead. Then God points out His Love as &lt;em&gt;Then said the LORD, Thou hast had pity on the gourd, for the which thou hast not laboured, neither madest it grow; which came up in a night, and perished in a night: And should not i spare Nineveh, the great city, wherein are more than sixscore thousand persons that cannot discern between their right hand and their left hand; and also much cattle. Jonah 4: 10, 11&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jeremiah 31: 3 - The LORD hath appeared of old unto me, saying, Yea, I have loved thee with an everlasting love: therefore with lovingkindness have i drawn thee.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;some-time-in-our-practical-life-we-feel-does-god-love-me&quot;&gt;Some time in our practical life we feel does God Love me?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything goes wrong in our life or if life is not going as we planned, we might think Does God Love me? Following reasons why people does not accept the truth easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;we-have-seen-love-fails-around-us&quot;&gt;1. We have seen love fails around us.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have seen human love fails in many places like marriages, relationships, etc. But Bible says Love never fails &lt;em&gt;(1 Corinthians 13:8)&lt;/em&gt;. This scripture talks about divine &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agape&quot;&gt;love&lt;/a&gt;. So God’s love is not like human love. It is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agape&quot;&gt;Agape&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;our-sins&quot;&gt;2. Our sins.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are not perfect and our sins some time make it difficult to believe “Nothing can separate us from God’s Love”. Psalms 139 : 13 says “For thou hast possessed my reins: thou hast covered me in my mother’s womb”. This means God loves us even before we were made, That proves even before we start doing something good, God loved us, hence doing something wrong can not separate us from God’s Love. God loves us not because of what we have done or what we are or by our good deeds. God loves us because He is Love. The perfect God loves the imperfect because He is perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bible says “&lt;em&gt;As far as the east is from the west, so far hath he removed our transgressions&lt;/em&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-sufferings-that-we-endure-in-this-life-actually-when-paul-wrote-the-letter-to-romans-he-was-dealing-with-such-situation&quot;&gt;3. The sufferings that we endure in this life. (Actually When Paul wrote the letter to Romans he was dealing with such situation)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peradventure sufferings make us thing God does not love us. But all the sufferings come results of sins in the world Practically saying, if we live a happy, successful life a lot of people does not like that, enemy does not like it, this  is why even if we are not doing anything wrong, trouble follows us and we should not be surprised, by seeing the troubles follow us. Every bad thing comes form the enemy, but we misunderstand as God does not love us. And we go ever further and say God why are you doing this? what have i done? But Jesus told &lt;em&gt;“These things I have spoken unto you, that in me ye might have peace. In the world ye shall have tribulation: but be of good cheer; I have overcome the world.”&lt;/em&gt; John 16: 33.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;five-pair-of-words&quot;&gt;Five pair of words.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul uses five pair of words to explain Nothing can separate us from God’s love. When we look at all five pair of words it clearly proves nothing can separate us from God’s Love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;a-life-death&quot;&gt;a. life, death.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death can not separate us from God’s Love. &lt;em&gt;But I would not have you to be ignorant, brethern, concerning them which are asleep, that ye sorrow not, even as others which have no hope. For if we believe that Jesus died and rose again, even so them also which sleep in Jesus will God bring with him&lt;/em&gt; 1 Thessalonians 4: 13,14. We have already seen the sin and the suffering that we endure in this life can not separate from God’s love. Neither death nor life can separate us from God’s love hence nothing in between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;b-angles-principalities&quot;&gt;b. angles, principalities.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pair of words says about angels and the fallen angels. Principalities refers to fallen angels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;c-things-present-things-to-come&quot;&gt;c. things present, things to come.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things present refers everything happen around us today. We don’t need to worry about today. Bible says &lt;em&gt;The LORD is my shepherd; I shall not want&lt;/em&gt; Psalms 23 : 1. Things to come says about feature, Roman 8: 37 says &lt;em&gt;Nay, in all these things we are more than conquerors through him that loved us&lt;/em&gt;. So what ever happens, even if it does not look good, do not give up, We are more than conquerors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;d-height-depth&quot;&gt;d. height, depth.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Height and depth can be interpreted as above heaven and bellow hell. Or it can be interpreted as ups and downs in life.       But the truth is neither of it can separate us from the Love of God. If we look at the life of Joseph, he was down, his brothers put him in pit. Joseph was sold to Potiphar(The captain of Pharaoh’s guard). His life was good there. When he ran away from the sin Joseph was held in prison. Then he raised again as Vizier(Like Prime minister). His life was full of ups and downs but eventually he became the Prime Minister of Egypt, and was given, the daughter of Potiphar to be his wife.
##### e. powers, other creature.
  Powers refers to mighty deeds or Miracles. Powers also refers to authority and the people who are in power and uses their power to do wrong things. Other creatures says about anything that has been created or What ever exists in this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These five pair of word clearly proves nothing can separate us from God’s Love.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://john8-32.github.io/godslove/nothing-can-separate-us-from-Gods-love.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://john8-32.github.io/godslove/nothing-can-separate-us-from-Gods-love.html</guid>
        
        <category>God</category>
        
        <category>Love</category>
        
        
        <category>GodsLove</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Traits of Rebekah</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;background-&quot;&gt;Background:-&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah died in Kirjatharba at the age of Hundred and seven and twenty. Abraham was old and stricken in age. He said his eldest servant of his house “Go unto my country, and to my kindred, and take a wife unto my son Isaac”. The servant asked Abraham, what if the woman is not willing to follow? Abraham said his servant, the LORD of heaven sware to me saying “He shall send his angel before thee” and you shall take a wife to my son. The servant took ten camels from his master and departed to Mesopotamia, unto the city of Nahor. He made his camels to kneel down without the city by a well of water at the time of evening. Then he said “O LORD GOD of my master Abraham, i pray thee, send me good speed this day and shew kindness unto my master Abraham”. And he continued “The damsel to whom i shall say, Let down thy pitcher, i pray thee, that i may drink; and she shall say, Drink and i will give thy camels drink also: let the same be she that thou hast appointed for thy servant Issac”. It came to pass, Rebekah came out, who was born to Bethuel, son of Milcah, the wife of Nahor, Abraham’s brother, with her pitcher upon her shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;characteristics-of-rebekah-&quot;&gt;Characteristics of Rebekah:-&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-the-damsel-was-very-fair-to-look-upon-a-virgin-neither-has-any-man-known-her-and-she-went-down-to-the-well-and-filled-her-pitcher-and-came-up-genesis-24-16&quot;&gt;1. And the damsel was very fair to look upon, a virgin, neither has any man known her: and she went down to the well, and filled her pitcher, and came up. Genesis 24: 16.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proverb 31: 30 says Favor is deceitful, and beauty is vain: but a woman that feats the LORD, she shall be praised. Verse 10 says “Who can find a virtuous woman? for her price is far above rubies.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 Peter 3: 4. But let it be the hidden man of the heart, in that which is not corruptible, even the ornament of meek and quiet spirt, which is in the sight of GOD of great price. 5. For after this manner in the old time the holy women also, who trusted in GOD, adorned themselves, being in subjection unto their own husbands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 Timothy 2: 9. In like manner also, that women adorn themselves in modest apparel, with modesty and sobriety; not with braided hair, or gold, or pearls, or costly array; 11. Let the woman learn in silence with all subjection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-the-servant-ran-to-meet-her-and-said-let-me-i-pray-thee-drink-a-little-water-of-thy-pitcher-and-she-said-drink-my-lord-and-she-hasted-and-let-down-her-pitcher-upon-her-hand-and-gave-him-drink-and-when-she-had-done-giving-him-drink-she-said-i-will-draw-for-thy-camels-also-until-they-have-done-drinking-and-she-hasted-and-emptied-her-pitcher-into-the-trough-and-ran-again-unto-the-well-to-draw-water-and-drew-for-all-his-camels-genesis-24-17-20&quot;&gt;2. And the servant ran to meet her, and said, Let me, I pray thee, drink a little water of thy pitcher. And she said, Drink my lord: and she hasted, and let down her pitcher upon her hand, and gave him drink. And when she had done giving him drink, she said, I will draw for thy camels also, until they have done drinking. And she hasted, and emptied her pitcher into the trough, and ran again unto the well to draw water, and drew for all his camels. Genesis 24: 17-20.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hard worker - she understood, he came from distance and gave water to her camels, She was practiced to work hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proverb 31: 13 - 17, describes about virtuous woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She seeketh wool, and flax, and worketh willingly with her hands. She is like the merchants’s ships; she bringeth her food from afar. She riseth also while it is yet night, and giveth meat to her household, and a portion to her maidens. She considereth a field, and buyeth it: with the fruit of her hands she planteth a vineyard. She considereth a field, and buyeth it: with the fruit of her hands she planteth a vineyard. She girdeth her lions with strength, and strengtheneth her arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-said-whose-daughter-art-thou-tell-me-i-pray-thee-is-there-room-in-thy-fathers-house-for-us-to-lodge-in-and-she-said-unto-him-i-am-the-daughter-of-bethuel-the-son-of-milcah-which-she-bare-unto-nahor-she-said-moreover-unto-him-we-have-both-straw-and-provender-enough-and-room-to-lodge-in-genesis-24-22---25&quot;&gt;3. And said, Whose daughter art thou? tell me, i pray thee: is there room in thy father’s house for us to lodge in? And she said unto him, I am the daughter of Bethuel the son of Milcah, which she bare unto Nahor. She said moreover unto him, we have both straw and provender enough, and room to lodge in. Genesis 24: 22 - 25.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebekah was very kind, She told the servant “We have both straw and provender enough, and room to lodge in”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proverb 31: 20 - She stretcheth out her hand to the poor; yea, she reacheth forth her hands to the needy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-the-damsel-ran-and-told-them-of-her-mothers-house-these-things-genesis-24-28&quot;&gt;4. And the damsel ran, and told them of her mother’s house these things. Genesis 24: 28.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebekah Ran to her home and let her family know about all the things happened at the well. It is important for a woman that it protects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-they-said-we-will-call-the-damsel-and-enquire-at-her-mouth-and-they-called-rebekah-and-said-unto-her-wilt-thou-go-with-this-man-and-she-said-i-will-go&quot;&gt;5. And they said, We will call the damsel, and enquire at her mouth. And they called Rebekah, and said unto her, Wilt thou go with this man? And she said, I will go.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rebekah told “I will go”. She was mentally prepared to leave her family and ready to live with her husband’s family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Psalms 45: 10, 11. Hearken, O daughter,  and consider, and incline thine ear; forget also thine own people, and thy father’s house; So shall the king greatly desire thy beauty: for he is thy LORD; and worship thou him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-she-had-said-unto-the-servant-what-man-is-this-that-walketh-in-the-field-to-meet-us-and-the-servant-had-said-it-is-my-master-therefore-she-took-a-vail-and-covered-herself-genesis-24-64&quot;&gt;6. For she had said unto the servant, What man is this that walketh in the field to meet us? And the servant had said, It is my master: therefore she took a vail, and covered herself. Genesis 24: 64.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebekah “took a vail, and covered herself”. This shows her humility and meekness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-issac-brought-her-into-his-mother-sarahs-tent-and-took-rebekah-and-she-became-his-wife-and-he-loved-her-and-issac-was-comforted-after-his-mothers-death&quot;&gt;7. And Issac brought her into his mother Sarah’s tent, and took Rebekah, and she became his wife; and he loved her: and Issac was comforted after his mother’s death.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebekah became Isaac’s wife, “and he loved her: and Issac was comforted after his mother’s death”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://john8-32.github.io/rebekah/traits-of-Rebekah.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://john8-32.github.io/rebekah/traits-of-Rebekah.html</guid>
        
        <category>Rebekah</category>
        
        <category>Characteristics</category>
        
        
        <category>Rebekah</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
